what's up guys this is the dumbbell
kneeling hip raise I've got Nicole
osoria my client here in Fort Lauderdale
with me and we're going to demonstrate
this this is going to light your glutes
on fire I posted this a couple weeks ago
everyone's loving it but we've made
improvements so the time is right for a
YouTube video all right she's going to
grab the dumbbell all right so I'm I'm
going to have my video guy Alex pan
around here as she's doing the movement
so you can get so you can check it out
from all angles because first of all I
elevated this bench so she could get
more range of motion what this is is a
weighted glute stretch so people say the
stretch is important the jewelry is
still out see my video on that
topic but we made this B stance because
stability was a factor here's what
you're trying to do right down right
down deep you want this portion right
here to be a weighted glute stretch you
want you're not just sinking into the
lunge you're also sinking laterally okay
now what I'm seeing people do is they
are turning into a hip airplane so after
I posted it this is what I saw people
just turning it into a kneeling hip
airplane where you're just doing kind of
like inal exteral rotation or more more
precisely um horizontal or transverse
plane adduction and abduction and that's
not what we want here yes this will
stretch the glutes a little bit but I
want you to go into a lunge so we
started going so so the whole purpose
was to sink back into the lunge like
this and and stretch stretch and go into
deep hip flexion so it was really
important you got to go into deep hip
flexion like you're doing so think of
this as a kneeling curtsy lunge if you
think of it as a curtsy lunge it all
makes sense then we added the B stance
so you have more stability and then
we've progressed in load Nicole is using
a 30 pounder I see a lot of people using
a five or 10 pounder that's great but
keep going we want to get strong at this
and I'm curious to see what the comments
look like because undoubtedly I'm going
to get people saying just squat just
lunge just curtsy lunge but what if you
just want extra glute stimulus what if
you're not looking for the quad stimulus
or the adductor stimulus then this is a
genius way to get the same exact
benefits of a squat a lunge a curtsy
lunge without hitting the quads without
hitting the adductors so you're getting
the same stretch stimulus in the glutes
without the added stuff that comes with
it so that's why this EX is taking off
but we keep improving upon it I'm
excited for you guys to give it a try so
just remember you're sinking back into
hip flexion and adduction and internal
rotation just try to stretch your glutes
maximally at the bottom some people like
coming up all the way some people
don't I just come up to about right here
some people will come way up as high as
they can go like
that it's up to you as long as you keep
the focus on the stretch Nicole wants to
show off her pump okay she wants to let
you guys know it's working it was
brutal all right guys so in addition to
what I just showed you with Nicole I
wanted to show you guys this footage
showing the optimal setup kind of the
differences between the first way I
taught it and its Evolution already just
a few weeks in it's already evolved a b
stce but you can do it the original way
too if you prefer that way but this is
the optimal setup requ
if you want to do it the new way what
would be optimal is if you just had a
bench on the floor with a big cutout or
or pit in the middle for you to sink
extra deep cuz you're going to need
these blocks for be stance stabilization
which I'll teach you in a second but uh
here's the way I first taught it okay
the first way was like this okay with a
leg up in the air and it was like this
but it's hard to balance this is hard to
balance especially some people have a
real tough time not falling off the
other thing is when I did it this way
here's what people turn it into they
would just stay here and go internal
external they just stretch this way like
it's a kneeling hip airplane and this is
not what you want you don't just want to
go from here to here you need to Lunge
back you want to stretch into hip
flexion too the new method you have your
foot down and you're going to sink back
into deep hip flexion with also some
rotation so just think of it as a
weighted glute stretch okay so here's
what we do now from here very stable
sink down stretch that glute come up
sink down
so just think sink into the stretch I
can't go any deeper here I'm at a Max
stretch for my glutes come
up this leg is just for stabilization
you're not putting you're not pushing
off this leg throw this to the other
side switch
up sink feel the stretch
so if you think of it as a kneeling
curtsy lunge you can't go wrong but be
sure to reach back and stretch deep hip
flexion with slight abduction and
internal rotation
and you can't go
wrong so years ago I came up with an
exercise called The Single Leg abducted
RDL and you basically elevate your foot
off to the side and it dawned on me that
this might be a preferential optimal
setup for this exercise too so I'm
trying to show you guys different
options here we have the standard bench
and we just put these pads on top these
are each uh I think they're two inches
tall so this just four so this would be
4 in
elevation so
now we Elevate the foot off to the side
and it's fine because she sinks
down this leg is just for stability
she's so she sinks down and back
and it's a super stable setup she's
sinking down and back into that
lunge thinking of like a deep squat or a
deep lunge getting maximum hip
flexion in combination with a little bit
of hip adduction and internal
rotation just add some stretch to the
upper glutes all right good now I wanted
to see if Nicole can use the 50 lb
dumbbell she has never gone above 30 she
repositioned this you've got to Tinker
around and figure out your optimal setup
all right let's see go down and hold
that stretch feel it yes great you don't
have to come up all the way you can come
up all that way or just go about right
there that's what I do alternatively you
can kind of thrust all the way up you
kind of round your you tend to round
your upper back you might like this more
coming up all the way but the goal of
this movement is for the stretch so
yes feel it yeah you like it yeah what
do you like more coming up all the way
or coming up halfway I feel better when
I come up all the way okay see she likes
the full range movement most I like the
length and partial movement either way
is fine okay so first before Nicole uses
weight she's just going to practice the
movement without weight first making
sure she gets that full deep stretch so
like this right here that's as deep as
you can go that's as good of a glute
stretch As It Gets now we're going to
add 50 lbs to that stretch okay go for
it yes see how she sinks all the way
down and even rotates a little bit this
is such a good glute stretches this is
you think about all the best exercises
you know you think about the best
isolation movements for your chest
dumbbell flies it's just a weighted PEC
stretch for for your hammies you know
dumbbell stiff leg deas that's just a
weighted hamstring
stretch and these are just a weighted
glute stretch so definitely ease into it
don't go crazy your very first time
doing it just get the movement down make
sure you're doing it right make sure you
feel the stretch and then add weight
over time just like you do every other
exercise we don't know what's best for
glute growth yet is the stretch more
important than the squeeze the jurry is
still out the plin 2023 study indicates
that they're equal so this is an easy
stretch movement you can do that doesn't
work any other muscles it's not going to
work your quads your Erectors your
adductors your hammies it's mostly all
glute and it's not going to fatigue you
systemically so add these in I don't
know what my opinion is yet on whether
to perform them first or second I kind
of think they should be done after a
squeeze movement because there's some
research that indicates when you pump a
muscle up like say you do hip thrust
first then you get more passive forces
in a pumped up muscle as you stretch it
than you do an unpumped muscle so I'll
show that research here there's two
studies so I kind of think you should go
hip thrust first then stretch but my
girls have been doing this first because
it's already set up I'm leaving this set
up in the gym they'll do this first and
then they go on to the rest of their
exercises but I'm excited to see what
you think about this I showed you the
free version just kneeling on the bench
with the leg up in the air then I showed
you the B stance or kickstand option and
now I show you the abducted version pick
the one that you like best I think this
is going to going to be most people's
favorite but it does require a lot of
equipment for the
setup all right so one more thing to
address so someone commented saying that
they've been doing this for years and I
was like I just made them up can you
show me a video and this is what she
sent me so go for it Nicole she sent me
a video of her doing a kneeling single
leg RDL and this has been popular for
around 10 years oh hand on hip yep so
this is working the grounded leg and
this knee is just there for support but
you're trying to put most of your weight
on the left leg here this is in contrast
to when we do it to try to stretch this
glute so if you watch Nicole now if you
put your put your foot on you can show
how now if we do this and then go wide
and then try it this way but put post up
post up right there
yeah now you see you're focusing on
using the right leg the grounded leg is
just for stability and this is the glute
you're trying to
work do you tell a difference how much
better is when we Elevate and yeah for
sure and we'll show it from this angle
too here you're working the gluten
hamstring on the grounded leg this is a
kneeling single leg RDL and then if we
switch it to the stretch the weighted
stretching exercise then it becomes like
this and then this becomes even better
when we Elevate the bench and then when
we provide an elevated surface for the
kickstand leg as well so I hope that
clarifies
things all right that's a wrap I hope
you enjoy the exercise I hope you enjoy
the video thank you Nicole she wants to
show off the glute pump if you like the
video please hit like please make sure
you're subscribed to my channel and
definitely leave me a comment let me
know how I'm doing I do listen to all
your comments some of it I'm not
responsible like if the audio is off
keep reminding us that's my video guy
Alex if Alex needs to improve tell him
we want to we want High qu on these so
thank you for watching I'm Breet contz
aka the glute guy